# ROYCHELLE ROWDEN

Visual + User Interface Designer



Relocating to Austin TX

773-828-4466

roychellerowden@gmail.com

§ roychelle.com

## **SKILLS**

- Responsive Design
- Prototyping
- Wireframing
- Personas
- Branding Design
- User Testing
- Research

# TOOLS

- HTML5
- CSS3
- JQuery
- Bootstrap
- Visual Studio
- InVisior
- Druna
- Wordpress
- Photoshop
- Illustrator
- Indesign
- Powerpoint
- Word
- Excel

#### SUMMARY

What is life about if you can't reinvent yourself? After several years of working as a landscape architect I felt my career prospects beginning to stagnate. My ability to find new employment began to narrow as firms increasingly closed their doors I had to make a choice to persevere on my current path or pivot and learn new in demand skills.

In 2013 I finally took a leap of faith and joined Startup Institute's program for Product Design which helped me develop the skills to gain a position as a User Interface Designer. My goal is to be a part of a design focused team in Austin TX creating cutting edge designs that solve problems and provide the best possible experience.

## **WORK HISTORY**

2014 - present User Interface Designer

Skidmore Owings & Merrill LLP - Chicago, IL

As the sole designer on my team I am responsible for driving all stages of the creation of interfaces that help SOM staff manage, digest and disseminate information. My duties include:

- Building low and high fidelity prototypes which communicate interactions to development team.
- Implementing UI with development team and created enhancements to optimize user experience.
- Customizing Drupal, Wordpress sites and other platforms so they are cohesive with SOM branding standards.

2013 - 2014 Freelance Designer

SoPact, In2itive Marketing & Classroom IQ - Chicago, IL Created branding, interface and Drupal site customization for small startups.

2007 - 2013 Associate

Hoerr Schaudt Landscape Architects - Chicago, IL

Project management of sites varying in scale and location. Production of construction documents, details and specifications 3D Modeling and photorealistic image rendering concept design to construction.

2006 - 2007 Designer

Mia Lehrer + Associates - Los Angeles, CA

Part of the Los Angeles State Historic Park Competition Team Research and concept generation Drafting, rendering, layout and graphic design of publications.

#### **EDUCATION**

2013 - 2013 Product & Design Certificate
StartUp Institute - Chicago, IL

2003 - 2006 Master of Landscape Architecture

Louisiana State University College - Baton Rouge, LA

1999 - 2003 Bachelor of Arts in Biology & Studio Art

Knox College - Galesburg, IL